
----------------  Illum  ----------------
          
           A Game About Light
 
             By Muxing Zhao

----------------  Story  ----------------

Illum is a game where you play as a lone
orb of light travelling through the
darkness of the universe, seeking for
things held secret within its mysterious
fields of strange, cube-like structures.

------------  The  Controls  ------------

Directional:

W - Move Forward
S - Move Backward
A - Move Left
D - Move Right

- OR -

↑ - Move Forward
↓ - Move Backward
← - Move Left
→ - Move Right

Switch Worlds:

1 - Switch to world 1, which is currently
    a difficult, hand designed level.

2 - Switch to world 2, which is an auto
    generating invisible maze.

3 - Switch to world 3, which is a test
    world with various things to mess
    with.

4 - Switch to world 4, which is a blank
    world with nothing inside it.

-------------  How To Play  -------------

Cube Variants:

Light - You are a source of light and
    you light up the world around you!

Cubes - These block your light and you
    can't travel through them.

Glass - These block travel, but allow
    light through.

Red Glass - These block travel, but allow
    light through and tints it red.

Green Glass - These block travel, but
    allow light through and tints it
    green.

Fade Cube - These blocks alternate as
    glass and solid and allow light when
    a glass. They block travel.

Invisible Cube - Block that can't be seen
    but blocks light and travel.

Door Cube - These blocks open only when
    the corresponding switch is turned
    on. Some have timers and some are
    permanent.

--

Switches:

Red Switch - Activated when a red light
    is shined on it.

Green Switch - Activated when a green
    light is shined on it.

--

Enemies:


Dark Light - These will turn you into
    a dark light if you shine your light
    onto them. Avoid them at all costs!

--

Other:

Light Orb - This is you! You control
    this little orb on its journey.

Checkpoints - Move over these to turn
    on. You respawn here on death.

Finish Orb - Move over this to complete
    the level!


---------  Thanks for Playing!  ---------


               ☀  ☀  ☀  ☀         


-----------------------------------------